Four years we wasted squabbling
over a peninsula's sovereignty.
And our two main battle Titans were
nearly shredded by the enemy fleet.
"Human ingenuity surpasses
and shatters Marley's Armor at last."
The press from other nations
is commending the Mid-East Forces.
Does this sound like a victory
for Marley to you?
Magath, do you care to comment?
General, I'm afraid the time has come.
That is, humanity has eclipsed
the Power of the Titans.
While we've been relying heavily
on Titans and colonial expansion,
other nations have been developing
weapons to counter us.
As a result, our strategy has
come back to bite us on the ass.
For the time being, our Titans remain
unrivaled when it comes to land battles.
However, if aircraft keep advancing at
this rate, bombs will soon fall like rain.
All while Titans, the devils of the earth,
can do nothing but look up and watch.
Do we not have any Titans with wings?
General, I'm trying to say
that the era of Titans--
I know.
In the near future,
we will lose our initiative in war.
No, perhaps we already have.
Though once the heroes who crushed
the Eldian devils, look at what we've become.
If I may, General?
Requesting permission to give counsel.
Zeke, the wonderboy. Go ahead.
We should resume the Paradis Island Operation
and recover the Founding Titan.
As Commander Magath was saying,
Marley needs to develop better weapons.
However, the world will not stand by and wait.
Our military needs time
to completely restructure.
But for that, the newspapers
of the world must read this:
"Marley Occupies Paradis
and Wields the Power of All Titans."
You have one year left
in your term, correct?
Yes, and I'm concerned that Colt can't
inherit the full power of the Beast Titan.
I see.
In your last year, you wish to redeem
yourself for your defeat four years ago?
That is correct.
The sick exploits of Grisha Jaeger
should be brought to an end
by none other than me, his former son.
"Midnight Train"
Sorry I bashed you to further my agenda, Colt.
Don't be. You were amazing.
To think, an Eldian being heard by the general!
There hasn't been a Beast
like you in its history.
Sometimes it reminds me
of the Founding Titan.
Why are you so special?
It's not like you have any royal blood.
Who knows? Guess I'll be dead
before we figure it out.
Oh... But when you inherit my memories,
you'll find out my big secret.
Secret? What is it?
The special way I wipe my ass.
Hope you don't tell anyone.
Too late. I want a report.
--Commander!
Everything down to the hairs on your ass.
Do you think Eldians get privacy?
No, sir!
You can conquer Paradis in a year?
It's more like I only have
one year left to try.
These past three years, every scout ship
we've sent to Paradis hasn't returned.
Zeke, what do you think of that?
Considering 32 ships were sunk, I can't
imagine a single Titan was responsible.
At least two Titans, including Eren Jaeger,
must have blocked their escape.
I agree. If we attack the island,
our ships will need support.
Yes. But it's more than their Titans
that pose a threat.
Wai--
It seemed like you were having a
good dream, so I didn't wake you.
I still haven't thanked you
for back then. Galliard...
Thank you.
Don't thank me.
If I inherited the Armored Titan nine
years ago, this wouldn't have happened.
My brother wouldn't have protected you
and been eaten by a Titan, either.
You saw Marcel's memories?
No, but I learned enough from
that girl before me, Ymir.
What an impressive name
for such a pitiful woman.
Isn't it thanks to her that we
got my brother's Jaw back?
Yeah, that's right.
What the hell were you doing on that island?
Getting saved by someone new every day?
Yeah.
I saw how you acted through her memories.
What's with that?
Pretending to be a reliable guy, huh?
I'd say you were imitating my brother!
Pock, let's not pick on people
who just took cannons to the face.
Quit calling me that, Pieck.
You all right?
It's been two months
since I've been a human.
I kinda forgot the whole bipedal thing.
By the way, Reiner...
You oughta see Gabi and the others.
They're worried about you.
Think I will.
I'm pooped.
Feels like ages since I've seen you.
Really? Even though we're
always fighting together?
Well, we might not have to for a while.
Let's hope so.
--This way.
--Sure.
Hey, if Titans lose their usefulness in battle,
what will happen to the
Warrior unit and us Eldians?
--A guy that lives near me said
the sea is so salty 'cuz he pisses in it.
--Mr. Braun will be fine.
--A guy that lives near me said
the sea is so salty 'cuz he pisses in it.
--I know.
--A guy that lives near me said
the sea is so salty 'cuz he pisses in it.
--Huh? That's...
--A guy that lives near me said
the sea is so salty 'cuz he pisses in it.
They're probably enemy soldiers
that survived the Pure Titan attack.
Once they get home, they'll talk about
how inhumane Titan warfare is!
It'll just make things
even worse for us Eldians!
"People of the world!
Let us kill the Subjects of Ymir!"
--Shit! Shit! Shit! Shit!
--Cut it out, Udo.
Don't beat up the city.
Reiner!
You're okay to walk?!
Yeah. Are you guys all right?
--Gabi.
--Yup!
--Udo.
--I guess.
--Zofia.
--Same old.
Falco.
Hello.
Hey! They said we're going back to Liberio!
Let's walk around till then!
Hey!
We never get chances like this!
Shouldn't Mr. Braun be resting?
I'm all right. Don't worry.
You go home and rest!
I'm coming, too!
Hold up, Gabi. Commander Magath
said that's not a place kids--
But I just saw him walking that way.
You worrywart.
Wait!
Huh?
You kids are too young for that store.
Aww!
Did you guys witness the bravery
of our Eldian goddess?!
Gabi took on the armored train
in place of 800 Eldian soldiers!
Man, Colt! You stink of booze!
Why'd you do it, you big idiot?!
Comrades! Do you have any idea
why this idiot risked her life?!
Well, I do! She did it to save
all your asses in the Eldian unit!
Yeah!
I'll go shut 'em up.
Let 'em have it.
Just this one night.
--Gabi! Gabi! Gabi...!
--Me! Me! Me...!
They're lifting her up again.
They shouldn't let my brother drink.
And Gabi gets carried away too easily.
Still, it's looking like she'll be the one
who inherits the Armored Titan.
Yeah. The girl who adores you
will inherit your Titan...
...and will live till she's 27.
If cannons don't shred her first, that is.
Are you fine with that?
What did you say? Are you insulting
the honor of inheriting one of the Nine?
If I report this, you and your whole
family will become Titan weapons.
W-Wait! Let me rephrase what I said!
I, Falco Grice, hope to be freed from
the evil blood of Ymir and my ancestors!
I pledge my life to Marley!
And what about the honor
of inheriting one of the Nine?
I would be proud to be an Honorary Marleyan
and be given the chance to display
my loyalty to our motherland!
Do you want to inherit the Armored?
Thank you!
The one who should inherit it... is me!
Yes.
Huh?
You have to rescue Gabi from
the dark future that awaits us.
"Armbands are used to differentiate the Eldian
'devils.' It is mandatory for Eldians in Marley
to wear their armband when they go outside.
Failure to do so will result in punishment."
We're back!
We made it back alive!
It's our beloved hometown, Liberio!
--We're home!
--Gabi...
Could you please tone it down?
Ow, ow...
You should've known
you can't hold your booze.
Who's the one who gave him the drinks?
He looked like he wanted some.
Unbelievable. How dare you spew
Pieck's kindness all over the train.
We should've shut 'em up last night.
I heard they kept hoisting you up.
Because of Colt!
I think it's fine. You deserved a bit of fun.
What you did was impressive.
Pieck!
Vice Chief Braun...
What if he's thinking the same as me...
and he wants us Eldians to be free from war?
Can I... trust him?
Later. Take it easy and enjoy the break.
Not me! It's back to training tomorrow!
Trying to boost your grades? Gimme a break.
I am not!
Hey, you two. Don't push yourselves too hard.
Dad!
Zeke...
Grandpa! Grandma!
I'm home!
You achieved great things, Zeke.
No, not yet.
Colt! Falco!
Colt!
Dad! Mom!
--Gabi!
Reiner.
You must be tired. Come home and rest.
Mom... I think I will.
Go on ahead!
For crying out loud!
Do you not know how to stand?
Are they injured soldiers, Mr. Koslow?
Huh? Stay outta the way, brat.
They're Eldians with emotional trauma.
Even our guys?!
It's from digging trenches
on the front lines too long.
All those bullets and bombs do it to you.
Boom!
Look! They fell over again!
You okay? It's all right!
Your armband's on the wrong arm.
It's okay. I'm sure you'll get better.
You don't have to fight anymore.
Boom!
Whoa!
Just like I planned, I blew the
armored train right off the tracks!
It actually worked! But as I ran away,
they fired a machine gun at me!
And just before I ate lead...
...Galliard protected me with the Jaw Titan!
Amazing, Gabi!
You and your bravery saved a bunch
of our soldiers! You're the savior of Eldia!
I'm so proud of you!
Reiner. Do you think Gabi
will become a Warrior?
Yeah. It's almost a given she'll
inherit the Armored Titan.
That's good to hear.
To think our family would have
two Warriors. I'm so proud.
If only those island devils disappeared,
we Eldians could finally be happy.
But, Reiner... Even you barely escaped
from the island devils, right?
Don't, Dad!
He survived on that island
of rotten devils for five years!
Even if it wasn't classified,
it's stuff he wouldn't wanna talk about.
You're right. Forgive me, nephew.
No, I can talk about it.
I infiltrated their military.
Every last one of 'em
was a savage, heartless devil.
During the entrance ceremony,
one of them started eating a potato.
The instructor yelled at them,
but they hardly seemed to care.
Said they stole it 'cuz it looked tasty.
Realizing they crossed the line,
they said they'd share half with him.
But the piece of potato they offered
wasn't even close to half.
Being considerate doesn't
even cross their minds.
They're truly beyond all help.
There was an idiot who forgot
why he went to the bathroom...
An insincere jerk who only
thought about himself...
An uptight oaf who only
cared what others thought...
A single-minded fool who charged ahead
and the chumps who followed him...
There were all sorts of people there.
And we were there, too.
My days there were true hell.
I've said too much. Forget it.
What do you mean, "all sorts of people"?
They're bad people, right?
That's right, Gabi. Those island devils
turned our world into hell.
There's no knowing when they'll attack
with giant Titans and flatten the world.
It's up to good Eldians like us
to make sure they never do.
Mmm.
Those who left us and fled to the
island deserved to be punished.
They're the ones who abandoned us.
What's wrong, Gabi? You seem down.
Aunt Karina's worried about you.
She says you changed after
coming back from the island alone.
Her 12-year-old son came back a grown man.
You can't really blame her.
It feels like you're lying.
Lying? About what?
I don't know, but I think Aunt Karina does.
I heard it was a soldier.
That's awful.
Good morning.
Everyone's here?
It's not every day we meet
in the war chief's room.
Where's the brass?
Not in this room.
Can't we just meet for some tea?
Right...
Now then,
the last battle made it clear that normal
weapons will overtake Titans in the near future.
The weaker Marley becomes,
the more the Eldian race is threatened.
Our existence is in danger.
To rectify this, Marley must obtain the
Founding Titan and Paradis' resources.
The world must be strongly reminded
of the threat that island poses.
To tell that story, we need a narrator.
The Tybur family will fulfill that role.
The family holding the War Hammer Titan?
It's said the Tyburs have never sent
the War Hammer Titan to enemy soil.
They're influential abroad for driving away
King Fritz during the Great Titan War.
The world will listen to them.
That's Pieck for you! Precisely!
But the Tyburs have been living
the life in their huge mansions.
Why come out of the woodwork now
and pretend to be heroes?
I know how you feel, but the Tyburs
are concerned about Marley, too.
But we--
If it saves our motherland
Marley, I'll be grateful.
Our Warrior unit can cooperate with the Tyburs
and serve as the backbone for restoring Marley.
Indeed. Here in Liberio,
there will be a festival soon.
Festival?
VIPs from abroad will be invited to hear
an announcement from the Tyburs:
"Within a year, we'll control Paradis Island."
The fate of Marley and all Eldians
rests in this plan. It cannot fail.
For the future of our motherland Marley,
we must join our hearts as one.
Galliard seems to have some complaints,
but he always gets the job done.
If that's all they're saying, I'm not concerned.
Except that one line of Zeke's.
Hmm?
"Not in this room," huh?
Am I going back...
...to that island?
Honorary Marleyan. Esteemed Warrior.
What he wanted to be. What he couldn't be.
Is the path that he's walked down
truly the right one?
Next episode: "The Door of Hope."